<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Chemistry on QuickAnswer</title>
    <link>https://quickanswer.site/categories/chemistry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chemistry on QuickAnswer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quickanswer.site/categories/chemistry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JEE Advanced Chemistry Paper-2 | Question-3 | Detailed Solution</title>
      <link>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-2-question-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-2-question-3/</guid>
      <description>The correct statement(s) about polymers is (A) The polymerization of chloroprene gives natural rubber, and (D) Ethene at 350-570 K temperature and 1000-2000 atm pressure in the presence of a peroxide initiator yields high density polythene.
The polymerization of chloroprene (2-chlorobutadiene) does indeed give natural rubber, which is a type of elastomer. This process involves the addition polymerization of chloroprene monomers to form a polymer with a cis-1,4 configuration.
Ethene (ethylene) can also be polymerized to form high density polyethylene (HDPE) using a peroxide initiator at high temperatures and pressures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEE Advanced Chemistry Paper-2 | Question-2 | Detailed Solution</title>
      <link>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-2-question-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-2-question-2/</guid>
      <description>To solve this problem, we can use the concept of molality, which is a measure of the concentration of a solute in a solvent. The molality of a solution is defined as the number of moles of solute per kilogram of solvent.
In this case, the molality of the solution is 0.1 mol/1.8 kg = 0.0556 mol/kg. Since the salt remains 90% dissociated in the solution, this means that 0.9 × 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEE Advanced Chemistry Paper-2 | Question-1 | Detailed Solution</title>
      <link>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-2-question-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-2-question-1/</guid>
      <description>To solve this problem, we can use the solubility equilibrium expression for PbSO4:
[Pb2+][SO4^2-] = Ksp
We can also use the dissociation constants for sulfuric acid to write the equilibrium expressions for H2SO4 and SO4^2-:
H2SO4 &amp;lt;=&amp;gt; H^+ + HSO4^- Ka1 = [H^+][HSO4^-]/[H2SO4]
HSO4^- &amp;lt;=&amp;gt; H^+ + SO4^2- Ka2 = [H^+][SO4^2-]/[HSO4^-]
We know that the concentration of H2SO4 is 1 M, and the concentration of Na2SO4 is 1.8 × 10^-2 M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEE Advanced Chemistry Paper-1 | Question-7 | Detailed Solution</title>
      <link>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-1-question-7-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-1-question-7-copy/</guid>
      <description>The electrochemical extraction of aluminum from bauxite ore involves the electrolysis of Al2O3 mixed with Na3AlF6 to give Al and CO2. This process is known as the Hall-Héroult process.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a step-by-step explanation of the process:
Bauxite ore, which is a mixture of aluminum oxide (Al2O3) and other minerals, is mined from the earth.
The bauxite ore is crushed and ground into a fine powder, called alumina.
The alumina is dissolved in hot aqueous sodium hydroxide (NaOH) to form a solution called aluminate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEE Advanced Chemistry Paper-1 | Question-6 | Detailed Solution</title>
      <link>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-1-question-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-1-question-6/</guid>
      <description>To solve this problem, you need to first determine the balanced chemical equation for the reaction between Cu(NO3)2 and KI. You can do this by examining the reactants and products and considering the types of ions present.
The reactants are Cu(NO3)2 and KI, which contain the ions Cu2+, NO3-, K+, and I-. The products are a brown solution and a precipitate. The brown solution likely contains Cu2+ ions, and the precipitate likely contains I- ions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEE Advanced Chemistry Paper-1 | Question-5 | Detailed Solution</title>
      <link>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-1-question-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-1-question-5/</guid>
      <description>The pH of a solution prepared by mixing 0.01 mol each of H2CO3, NaHCO3, Na2CO3, and NaOH in 100 mL of water can be determined by calculating the concentrations of the various species present in the solution.
The initial concentrations of the various species present in the solution can be calculated as follows:
• H2CO3: 0.01 M • NaHCO3: 0.01 M • Na2CO3: 0.01 M • NaOH: 0.01 M
The equilibrium concentrations of the species present in the solution can then be determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEE Advanced Chemistry Paper-1 | Question-4 | Detailed Solution</title>
      <link>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-1-question-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quickanswer.site/posts/jee-advanced-chemistry-paper-1-question-4/</guid>
      <description>The standard molar enthalpy of formation of HgO(s) at 298 K (X) can be calculated using Hess&amp;rsquo;s law of constant heat summation. This law states that the enthalpy change of a reaction is independent of the pathway taken to reach the reaction. Therefore, the enthalpy change of any reaction can be calculated by adding the enthalpy changes of the individual reactions which make up the overall reaction.
In this case, the reaction of combustion of Hg(g) to form HgO(s) can be broken down into two individual reactions as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
